First of all, the first function is the function of our virtual model editor.
Before that, I want to tell you that we have updated some pre-set clothes and so on in the software.
You can download it by clicking the download button in the upper left corner.
You can download some of our clothes and other things.
For example, virtual models and so on.
There is a guide.
After opening a virtual model, you can adjust the height and chest of the model in the virtual model editor.
When you choose a attribute,
the attribute corresponding to it in the 3D window,
it will be displayed in yellow.
The path is also on the B站.
Then at the bottom, you can choose the type of detail attribute.
For example, you can choose the human model.
The feature of the human model is that you can adjust a lot of parts.
But because this is a detail adjustment,
once you change a little detail,
the difference will be more obvious.
So I suggest that everyone still uses the basic one.
Then you can also choose the unit angle.
Then when you adjust it normally,
we can first lose the overall height or the overall chest.
Then why is there such a function?
It's because the back of our software,
that is, this version now,
automatically adjusts the plate.
Then you can download it online.
In the process of making clothes,
you must first go online to search for the type of clothes you want to make,
and then find some plates that match it.
The plates that you usually search on the Internet,
in general, they all match the clothes in real life.
For example, if you search for a large dress,
it may give you a size.
This large dress is the height,
1.6 meters or 1.65 meters.
If a girl wears it,
then you can go online to search for her.
For example, her height is 1.65 meters,
her chest is 84 meters.
You put that,
this is a standard size.
Just to clarify for everyone.
When everyone usually makes clothes,
there is actually a standard size.
Then you can enter the height and width.
After that,
you put the clothes in such a,
a normal model body.
Then put it on.
After putting it on,
you can put it on your model
with the automatic adjustment tool.
Then some changes are made according to the body shape of your model.
So here we will have
the virtual model editor of our default model.
Then after adjusting the size,
you can save it.
You can use it next time.
I haven't done a live broadcast for a long time.
I'm a little nervous today.
Then,
yes, I'm very nervous.
I feel my hands are shaking.
Then,
we can now put a virtual model in.
This is an OBJ model.
Then,
in this version now,
after inserting an OBJ model,
we can use this deformation axis
to do this model.
Do a deformation to this model.
Then you can do a deformation in three directions.
Yes,
I've been really,
really nervous recently.
I haven't done a live broadcast for a long time.
Then,
now this model can be
paralleled in all directions.
You might need to open ShiftX before.
Now you don't need it.
And now there is a ground or center in the right-click menu.
You can see it.
You can move it to this coordinate center with one click.
Then,
I'll show you how to create that test suit.
Because we,
whether it's automatic wear or automatic adjustment board,
it's all based on the model.
Yes,
it's all based on the model's test suit information.
To do some deformation.
So,
we're going to give you a default model first.
Create a test suit.
Then we can open this created test suit.
After that,
you can follow
the reference position on our picture.
Draw a measurement line on the virtual model.
The measurement line we usually use is the same.
Click three points and then it will create its own measurement line.
Have a live broadcast.
Then,
if we accidentally draw this measurement line crooked,
you just right-click and delete it.
Then,
every time you create a measurement line,
it corresponds to this.
The clothing version will be automatically generated.
Then,
for example,
this model,
because now,
when I was recording the video,
the model was symmetrical.
Then,
if your model is not symmetrical,
you can turn off this symmetry.
Then,
you can measure some measurements
between your left arm and your right arm.
Oh,
the created test suit.
Wait a minute.
I'm going to launch a secret weapon.
Two mouse buttons.
Here.
In the position I clicked with my mouse.
This is the created...
Oh, sorry.
This is the created test suit.
Sorry.
Next to it is the automatic dress.
Okay.
Then,
the created...
Because the data is not available,
when I say I'm Teacher Zhu,
I'm not Teacher Zhu.
Then, after creating finished it,
click on the app,
you will see a strange red suit.
穿在我這個模特的外面
穿,
然後
就可以拖拽一下
and let this suit tightly
wrap around our model
and then don't have any weight.
Well,
after creating,
Then in the later version, you can use this model, which is the model of the information of Sichuan.
Then we open a project file that is worn by our default virtual model.
Because no matter which new Sichuan service or adjustment version these functions,
you have to switch between two models with Sichuan service information.
Then in order to speed up the conversion, we first increase the particle diameter to 20.
This can speed up the simulation a little bit faster.
Then simulate a little bit.
After the simulation is done, we open the little fireman with the Sichuan service information.
Then we open the little fireman with the Sichuan service information.
It's not a fireman, right?
It seems to be a fireman.
Then click on the automatic adjustment version tool.
There is a holdup of the version below.
It actually refers to, for example, the curve on your side.
Its curve value.
The larger you adjust, the more it can maintain this holdup.
Then save the size of the sticker.
That is to say, when you transform this version,
the size of the sticker will not be reset.
When you transform this version, the size of the sticker will not be reset.
Then just wait a moment.
Wait for a calculation time in the back.
Then after the calculation, you will find that the size of the version will be changed.
Then it will match the new model you just imported.
And these curves and the stickers on my pants are all there.
Then if you don't want to change the size of all the clothes,
you just want to put this whole set of clothes on another model,
you just click on the automatic adjustment.
Then the automatic adjustment is the same.
If you don't use our default model,
or you use the model with the Sichuan service information,
you can use the model with the Sichuan service information.
Yes, the recording is in the official ID of BJMD.
Yes, this is our new model.
The posture is different, but it's okay.
Try to be in the same posture.
Don't be too ridiculous.
But in fact, we will identify your model.
Its wrist is in the position.
Then you can see this is our new model.
It's called Hanna.
Then this comparison picture on the left,
we didn't use the automatic adjustment version.
Then on the right,
we used the automatic adjustment version.
You can see that the size of the version is different.
It's not necessarily a must-have model.
You can use any model with the Sichuan service information.
Then why do I keep emphasizing the default model with everyone?
It's because our default model
brought the information of the Sichuan service itself.
There will be a replay later.
Then because of this conversion of the Sichuan service,
and the function of the automatic change of the Sichuan service,
it will have a stage volume in the background.
So when you use these functions,
it's best to make sure that your clothing has a larger particle case.
Then let's first put in a basic cheongsam.
Then change it to a pair of high heels.
In the new version,
we have some settings about high heels.
In fact, it is an ancient style.
You can change our model from flat heels to high heels.
In fact, it is like this.
Then let's first put on some pieces that can't be used.
In fact, when I first used this function,
I suddenly found that
when I wear high heels,
I can always point the heel up, up, up, up.
Then the shoes will be deformed.
Then here's a little thing I want to tell you.
When you usually use Marvelous Designer,
if the model you use is like Hana,
when the chest and waist difference is relatively large,
you can add such a structure on your clothes.
It's this zero-shaped structure.
It's called the Shendao.
Then if you use the Shendao,
you can,
because here,
it's sewn up.
It's actually like there's a piece in the middle.
You put it with a sewing line like this.
Sewed up.
After it's sewn up,
it naturally has more fabric here on the chest.
Then there's less fabric here.
It looks more like a human kick curve.
Can the model who changed the movement after wearing the Shendao suit?
Yes, it can.
But I suggest you change it under the A-pose.
Just wear these clothes.
This step is actually a relatively early step.
Then after you wear it,
you change your posture again.
I usually change my posture at the end.
How to import action animation into Mac version MD?
You open an Arambic file.
As long as it brings the action by itself,
you can.
Because unless you have your own,
I feel that Mac is not the same as that.
It's all about opening the action.
Complicated models usually wear clothes.
Just wear it normally.
Add a layout and then wear it.
Then now we have his clothes.
Then I will make his sleeves a little longer.
Then, for example,
some clothes,
his sleeves are very long, very long.
Then we usually don't
use a fixed needle to pull it.
Or pull it when you open the model.
But now,
in fact, there used to be this function.
It's just that you don't usually know.
Now we've integrated it into the measurement.
For example,
we can draw a measurement line on the model.
Then put this side
on the virtual model tool.
Stick it on.
Then open the model.
After that,
this dress will
be worn by itself.
Then wear it yourself.
Then after wearing it,
I feel that
the position is almost the same.
You can delete this measurement line.
This model is called Hana.
Not called Miao Miao.
It's not called Ran Ran.
It's called Hana.
Why is it called Miao Miao or Ran Ran?
Where did these names come from?
It's just a general way.
It's very obvious.
Then I thought
the sleeve was long after I finished.
I still cut it off.
Then the latest version of the
solar panel external expansion
has a wrinkle in the direction.
Then you'll say that it's a Advanced.
In the previous step,
we might have to create a line first,
then cut it off and delete it.
These steps are more
complex and longer.
This strand is very small.
And this child is very cute.
This child is very cute.
So this is the first layer of the
structure.
So I think it's very important
to make it long.
In fact,
this is a very soft hairstyle.
I think it's really important
to do this.
Right,
this is a pretty long figure.
Right now,
In the new version, we can also use the function of the
extension tool to create a reference line, and when the mouse is placed on this reference line, it can be expanded along the left and right sides at the same time.
Then, after the expansion is completed, I feel that I seem to be a little too much, so I will adjust it again.
In the past, there was a reference line when the extension tool was opened, but there was no reference line when it was compressed, and there is also a reference line in the new version, so you can refer to its effect.
Yes.
Then, in the previous version, if there is a reference line on the top of the board, and you are using the extension tool, the reference line will not move along with it, and it will also move along with it in the new version.
Why are there so many chats that I don't understand? Did Mr. Zhu Zhu come over there?
I don't think so.
I don't understand either.
I'm confused.
At first, I thought it was Mr. Zhu Zhu who came over there.
Okay.
Then draw the internal line.
Then, in the new version, there is a function to align to the internal line.
In the past, if you want to align to the internal line, you may need to add a dot, add a banana dot, and so on.
You have to cut it, and so on.
Now you don't have to.
Now you can just align to the internal line.
But because it will recognize.
If there are a lot of internal lines on a board, it will automatically recognize the one that is closer to it.
Mr. Zhu Zhu.
Who is Cio Cio's cousin?
After deleting the dot, is it automatically a curve line now?
No.
After deleting the dot, you have to select the dot right arrow to convert it to a curve line dot.
It will have a curve line.
It's just that I operated faster at the time and didn't see it.
Then I changed the posture of the model.
Then after I changed my posture that day, my colleague said that this posture is very similar to Ma Baoguo.
Then I broke.
I said it seems to be really a bit like that.
I feel like I'm about to play Tai Chi.
I feel like I'm about to cheat and sneak my two-year-old MD.
Oh, it's not two years old.
It's the newly established MD Hana.
I really.
Then he told me that it feels like this Hana will rush out at any time and give me a set of spring.
I broke it at that time.
I said, how can there be this feeling?
How can it feel like Ma Baoguo?
Then I found out later that I said I didn't even know if it was this.
Is this the problem of running or the problem of this posture?
There is always a feeling that it is very sticky.
Then in the new version, if you put the mouse on our fabric, you can preview the texture of the fabric.
Why is the image so beautiful?
Recently, there is also something in the MMD area.
Ma Baoguo?
I saw a Ma Baoguo's keyboard before.
Why cancel the reading of target?
This function is particularly useful.
This function is not canceled.
Then, the next one I want to introduce to you is the dynamic fold function.
If you open the carving mode, it will automatically.
Yes, yes.
You can create a dynamic stroke brush by dragging the brush.
Then you can restore the stroke to the original state without using the dynamic stroke brush.
Do you have the function to change the movement of the M of Target?
No, I don't know how to use the M of Target.
Then you can adjust the size of the dynamic stroke brush and the focal point.
The focal point is like this, because when you change the focal point, there will be a large area in the middle.
Then the stroke in this focal point area will not be deformed.
That is to say, only the stroke in the circular area outside the brush will have a dynamic stroke.
So the focal point will not be deformed.
The larger the focal point, the larger the center will be.
The brush strength is the size on the right.
In fact, only the size has no strength.
Then if you use the manual version, you can do it.
The manual version has a pressure sensor.
Can the dynamic stroke brush be retained after switching back to the resolution mode?
No, it can't.
Can you identify the pressure sensor of the manual version?
Yes, I can identify the pressure sensor of the manual version.
It's just because my home doesn't have a manual version, so I can't show it.
The manual version is in the company.
Don't ask me why I didn't bring it back.
Then the brush with the strength is the one with the carving.
Then this is the dynamic stroke.
The dynamic stroke is a little different from that one.
It's not a direct carving.
It's to imitate or simulate the stroke effect we have in the simulation mode.
Then you can drag this board.
If you switch back to the simulation mode, you can't maintain this stroke state.
If you want to maintain it, remember to look at the shape and draw it.
Then there is a reality below.
This reality was actually a long time ago when we first named it.
Why is this thing called reality?
In fact, it means that the higher its value, the closer it is to some of the wrinkles in the simulation mode.
Then the lower the reality, the more strange its wrinkle shape is.
The more strange it is, the more strange it is.
The more strange it is, the more strange its wrinkle shape is.
The distribution of its wrinkles is different from the high reality.
It's a little bit like that kind of evaporation wrinkle.
It's not much different from the wrinkle.
It's a little bit like that kind of evaporation.
It's a little bit like that kind of evaporation wrinkle.
Then set the level again.
For example, if you want to move two layers of clothing together, you have to set the level to 2.
Then you must click on the layer on the outside, not the layer on the inside.
If you click on the layer, you actually set two layers.
The layer outside will not move with it.
Then you can change the simulation mode from CPU to GPU.
The new version can be restored at most before you open the sculpt mode.
The new version has a free trial time of one month for each friend, so you can download it on the official website.
After watching the live broadcast, go to the official website and get the trial version for one month.
It seems that many friends don't know about this.
We obviously have Bilibili, but everyone still doesn't know about this.
For example, if I use GPU simulation now, because my cheongsam has two layers,
even if you set the layer level, the inner layer will still be broken.
So when there are many layers like this, I will switch to GPU simulation and do some simulation.
Then everyone may find that I have reduced the authenticity.
Why? Because imagine it.
Because this cheongsam is very tight, and the clothes are very tight.
If you pull it in the real world, the wrinkle is a bit difficult to pull out.
So you have to pull it out.
This will reduce the authenticity.
This will make it easier to pull out these wrinkles.
Is this easy to learn?
It's easy to learn. It's especially easy to learn.
Marvelous Designer is super easy to learn.
It's simple and easy to learn.
It's okay.
As long as you follow the steps of the official website and start learning a little bit,
you can learn it very quickly.
If you can't do it, add a group.
Add a group first.
Sit in the group first.
There are a lot of young people in the group who have just started using Marvelous Designer.
Read the new model of Dream of Targets.
The new model is getting smaller.
I haven't met you.
Your unit may have been chosen wrongly.
What is transformation?
I'm not Mr. Zhu.
I'm not Mr. Zhu Zhu.
I'm not.
I didn't use a translator.
But I can manually translate it for you to listen to.
If I get tired later, I can switch back to a lower-level voice.
After using this dynamic wrinkle brush, remember to use a round brush.
Slightly round the area around it.
Then you can adjust it again.
The shape of the wrinkle you want to adjust.
Like this.
When will Mr. Zhu come out?
Mr. Zhu is coming soon.
Then I'll speed up a little bit.
Let everyone see Mr. Zhu quickly.
And then you may have noticed that I've clicked a lot on that screen just now.
The reason is that when I was recording, I found out that this seems to be a bug.
And then those few functions will suddenly all light up all at once.
And then my compulsion really can't stand it.
I'll just click on them one by one.
And then in the new version, we still support the texture of Substance.
And then you can put Substance's SBSAR file into Marvelous Designer.
And then by opening this high-quality rendering, you can make this material more realistic.
And then in addition to the repetitive texture type that we used to have,
we now have a unified texture.
This one.
Oh, the unified UV option.
That is to say, for example, you have a UV picture.
If you want to use this kind of slow-motion picture of UV as the texture,
you can directly choose that mode.
Choose the unified texture mode.
Oh.
Because I chose this.
And then because if you use this mode, it will detect your UV picture.
So if you change the UV layout in the UV editor,
its texture will change.
So you have to make sure your UV layout is normal.
You can also adjust the size of this texture by repeating V and repeating U.
If you are an ordinary texture,
you can use the editor texture tool to pull its texture.
Why are you still discussing whether Mr. Zhu is a man or a woman?
Mr. Zhu is a man.
Mr. Zhu didn't fall asleep, I guess.
I guess.
Maybe he fell asleep.
And then change the color.
There are some options that can be changed in Substance's material.
You can also change some of the options in Marvelous Designer.
After changing, we can save this fabric.
And then we can continue to use it next time.
But this fabric can only be opened in Marvelous Designer.
It can't be used in Substance.
And then you can preview the texture of this fabric in the paint window on the left.
You can preview the texture of this fabric.
Technically, it should be able to fit inek.
Make sure you did get it!
If not, there must be a problem!
Some time later, while he tries to open one of thevideo files.
Yeah.
No problem.
Seriously.
When you're done,
OK.
Okay.
After you're done,
beauty,
there's no temper.
OK.
Can't concentrate all the time.
In the latest version, in the UV editor, we have newly added the function of physical baking.
Then, first of all, there is the function of UV exposure.
Through UV exposure, we can pour out the UV grid of this clothing, and then we can make some adjustments and check it in other software.
A strange black piece appeared in the upper right corner.
Then you can set the color of its frame and the resolution, not the resolution, the pixels.
Then next to it is the function of baking pattern.
You can see that when we choose the baking pattern, we can set its size.
Then below is its UV area, which is the area where we pour out this UV pattern.
Then below this is the type of pattern we bake.
For example, we can bake.
We can set the color of the baking pattern, the metal degree pattern, the hair line, and the roughness map.
Then you can slightly increase the size of this, and then click save.
What can we do with this?
We can make clothes.
We can make shoes.
We can make pants.
We can make bags.
Then you can see that some of our UV patterns have been saved.
Then after that, we can switch the pattern type back to the unified pattern.
After that, we can add these patterns again.
What can we do?
Work position.
Oh my god.
This is one of your work positions.
Some companies, when they recruit people, they increase the number of designers.
I can't tell you which companies.
Anyway, some companies, if you buy a designer, they may consider this.
You can choose this, select this.
It's okay, I think.
It's not a big deal for me.
I'll just go to the site again.
Then I'll look inside it.
Let's first pour in a text.
Everyone just, me and the editor, you may have heard me say that we can now type transparency and metal.
But it has nothing to do with me
I am a fat guy
A big fat guy
I am sorry
to let your fantasy
go to waste
Maybe I am
a chubby
Why is the model Miao Miao again?
What is Miao Miao?
I must
ask you next time
And then
when you draw
there are several types
For example, RGB or Alpha
Some people
may use RGB
if the texture is
JPG
It is used to identify
the transparency
And then
if it is PNG
with its own Alpha channel
you can use Alpha mode
I said stop
Stop
Do you have a backpack tutorial?
Yes
But you need to
go to
YouTube
to learn
And then
when you change the picture
it will automatically
switch to RGB mode
So be careful
I used to
use Alpha mode
I was wondering
how the transparency
looks weird
Then I realized
I forgot to change the mode to Alpha
And then
we can drag a pattern
to the metal here
By adjusting the metal
below
it can make the clothing
have this metal glow
What hardware
do I use on my computer?
The recording computer
is 1080 or 1060
This is a relatively
old computer
And then
by adding the highlight
and
the metal
you can control
the metal distribution
In short,
you can try to add
the highlight and the metal
And then
from here
I feel like
the painting style is not right
he is going to
give me a whole set
And then after changing the texture
I still think he is going to
give me a whole set
And then
in the new version
I feel like
I can keep the color
of the sword
in the shape of the sword
The color
Yes, I feel like
it might be the color
Because when Ma Baoguo
filmed that video
didn't he wear a pink dress
inside?
Pink underwear
not autumn clothes
And then
there is a little story I want to share with you
about the highlight
I don't know
if you guys
often use the highlight function
You can actually
import the OBJ
into the highlight
The highlight
is the component
And then
you can use the highlight
to draw a line
on the top
Why
do models wear underwear
on the top?
Don't you believe us?
There are so many highlights
Hmm
Oh, I can send you this copy
Go to the other 3D software
and process it
I'll pretend that I didn't see
this highlight
Now there is the highlight
Yes, I just
put a pearl
into the highlight
Then you can add pearls along the edge
You don't have to
add the copy manually
But you will find
how this pearl will transform
Because the highlight
follows the grid of your clothes
Because the highlight follows the grid of your clothes
And if the grid of your clothes
is stretched
The highlight will also be stretched
Then
add pearls along the chest
After adding pearls
I found that the transformation here
is more serious
Because this is a straight line
And this corner is a sharp corner
It's easier to
change the shape of the grid
There are some other problems
And then
I will adjust the position of the highlight
Remember to add a group
If you don't have a group
I want to see
What am I doing later
Draw the EJ
Oh, right
There is one thing I want to talk about
It's about drawing the hair line
Because
I just told you
about drawing the hair line
And then
A lot of friends asked me
About the hair line
Because the hair line in MD
Is in the form of a hair line
It makes the clothes look like
The kind of hair line
It's a kind of shadow
But some friends found that
In the UV editor
In the hair line picture
There is no hair line
It's because
Our drawing
Is based on the 2D window
So the 2D window
Doesn't have the effect of the hair line
So if you use the UV editor
To draw the hair line
You may not be able to draw the hair line
Under what circumstances
Can we draw the hair line
If we want to draw the hair line
There is a unified UV coordinate
When we open the OBJ
Remember to hook it
I have two mouse
Let my mouse overlap with this
Okay
The unified UV coordinate
Hook it here
After that
There is an image of hair line
Remember to hook the image of hair line
And then you can
Draw the hair line
This is the hair line of the hair line
You're talking about the famous line, I get it. You're talking about the famous line, the famous line of OVJ, uh, there will be some problems out there
That's true. So the famous line, uh, you have to make it a little bit wider
And then there's the comparison of the two, um, the two lines of the line and this is the 2D one, which is the one that's been prepared
It doesn't have the edge of the line, but if you use the OBJ to get it out, it will have the edge of the line
The famous line is very thin and if you take it out, it's because it's in the OBJ format, so it's in the network format
If you take it out, the face will be gone as soon as you take it off, so it's better to do it in front of the other three places
Yeah, uh, it's actually nothing after that, uh, add a sticker and then
The new version of the sticker because the previous sticker can't cross the board
And now the sticker can cross the board. After you add a sticker, you open it and then you select this option
And then you set the size of it and the board will automatically oh no no this sticker will automatically cross the board
I'll think about what's next
Oh, there's another one at the back where you can set the distance between it and the axis
Because we used to deal with this gap when we were dealing with this gap
The overlap between the line and the sticker is sometimes more random
Sometimes you want the sticker to be below and then you adjust the distance between it and the axis
It's a little bit smaller and now you can cross the board
Yeah, so if I don't introduce it to you, you don't know about this and then the relationship can be introduced